Name: Leandro Rodrigues de Souza

Position: Senior Oracle and Postgresql DBA

E-mail: leandrosouza.dba@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/leandro-souza-28613250/

GitHub: https://github.com/LeandroSouzaDBA/Resume

• Profile:

Leandro's main background is in Oracle and Postgresql Databases since 2008, advanced customer and systems supports.

He also has experience with Cloud, Virtualization, On Premise Hardware Infrastructure, and Linux Operational Systems.

He has experience with Technical Documents/Manuals creation.

• Main Skills:

OracleDB

PostgresqlDB

Linux (General)

Support for Advanced Users

Virtualization

Hardware Infrastructure

• More Skills:

SQL, MSSqlServerDB, MongoDB, MysqlDB, MariaDB, Scrum, GIT, Bash, AWS, Azure, Windows and Linux OS: (RedHat/CentOS/Rocky/Ubuntu/AIX/more) and more.

• Personal Interests:

He loves to travel, drink beers and make barbecues, stay with your family and friends, learn about the universe and technologies. In addition, he have a great old video games collection.

• Experiences:

Trópico SA | Senior DBA | Home Office after 2020 Pandemic Since June 2017

Telecommunications Company

- Costumers Telecom Companies Support: OI, Telefônica, Vivo, Claro and Embratel.
- Support for Advanced Users/Analysts/Developers.
- Postgresql and Oracle Stand Alone and Dataguard Administration.
- Backup/Restore with RMAN, Expdp and Impdp.
- Database Monitoring, Performance Tuning and Issues Troubleshooting.
- Hardware Installation and Configuration.
- Physics and Virtual Servers Administration with VMWare, OracleVM and KVM.
- Openstack Infrastructure Creation, Hardware and System Requirements.
- Hardware Infrastructure on AWS Cloud.
- Operational Systems Linux and Windows Installation and Configuration.
- Operational Systems Advanced Support.
- Advanced Shell Scripts.
- Own Systems Supports.

- HAProxy (Processes Balancing), KeepAlived, ETHs Bond.
- Technical Documents Creation.

24x7 DBA Sênior Support – On Notice with SLA.

Owner and Participant of Change Managements.

Magazine Luiza | Senior DBA | On Site 2012 to 2017 Large Retail Company

- Methodologies: ITIL v3, LEAN IT, Kaizen.
- PeopleSoft: PeopleTools, ProcessScheduler, Tuxedo, WebServer, Domain.
- Oracle 10g to 12c Stand Alone, PSU, Fixes and Migrations.
- Oracle RAC, Grid Infrastructure, OEM, Dataguard, ASM, RMAN.
- Oracle PLSQL, SQLTune, AWR, Expdp, Impdp, Load and Treat Data.
- MSSQLServer 2008 2012, Cluster, TSQL, Report Services, Bkp/Restore.

24x7 DBA Sênior Support – On Notice with SLA.

Owner and Participant of Change Managements.

Softon Sistemas Inteligentes | Senior DBA | On Site 2011 to 2012

Antifraud Banking Company

- Costumers Bank Support: Caixa Econômica Federal, Banrisul and Banco Renner.
- Database Infrastructure in Cloud Amazon AWS.
- Oracle 10g to 11g Stand Alone.
- Postgresql 8 to 9.
- Tuning with Big Data.

IBM Brazil | Prime DBA | Hybrid – On Site and Home Office 2008 to 2011

Worldwide Technology Company

- Oracle 8i to 11g Stand Alone SAP Basis and Relacional, DR-Desaster Recovery in IBM-AIX.
- SQLServer 2000/05/08 Relacional, AS, IS, RS, TLSQL, Windows Server Cluster.
- Progress.
- Tuning, Monitoring, Support to Advanced Users, Infrastructure, Issues Troubleshooting, more.

DBA PRIME (Senior):

OnSite: - TECBAN and SAINTGOBAIN Companies.

Online: - WTORRE, ODEBRECHT, CARREFOUR, CYRELLA, NEXXERA, SOFISA,

COPERSUCAR, Others.

Working with Projects and Ongoing.

24x7 DBA Prime Support – On Notice with SLA.

Owner and Participant of Change Managements.

Cadbury Adams Brazil | Junior DBA | On Site 2005 to 2008

Worldwide Food/Candy Company

- DBA/AD: Oracle9i and SQLServer2000.
- Projects Analise and Management.
- Level 1 and 2 Support: Service-Center Team Leader, Support for Advanced Users, Computer Equipments Support.

Support on trips in national territory.

• Other Experiences (On Sites):

Atento: (Level 2 Support Analyst – Telefônica Speedy) – 2007 (at night).

Unifran: (Trainee – Informatics Student Center) – 2002-2004. **Autonomous:** (Home Computing Technician) – 1997-2002.

Skills:

• Education

Bachelor's degree – Information Systems (Systems Analyst)

Franca University (UNIFRAN) 2001 – 2005

Certifications and Trainings

- AWS Webinars EC2, S3, AMI, VPC, RDS, others 2022 and 2023.
- Azure (Az-900) Fundamentals Ka Solutions 2023.
- SCRUM Ka Solutions 2017.
- ORACLE Workshop I e II Ka Solutions 2016.
- GUOB and ORACLE OPEN WORLD (Brazil) 2014, 2015, and 2016.
- ORACLE Database 12c 2015.
- ITIL Foundation v3 2010 and 2013.
- ORACLE Database 10g, 11g 2006 and 2010.